MIGUEH KENMOE Dirane

IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

\(\text{Phone: +237 656304392} \)

⊠ Email: migueh.dirane@gmail.com

Portfolio: migueh-dirane.github.io

PROFILE

Experienced IT Support Technician with a successful track record in overseeing IT systems, hardware, software, networking, and technical support. Equipped with comprehensive knowledge and expertise, capable of delivering a diverse range of IT services that significantly enhance company productivity and performance.

SKILLS

- Team collaboration
- Information confidentiality
- Problem solving
- Adaptability and flexibility
- Organizational skills and innovations
- Excellent communication

- Virtualization (Vmware ESXI, Hyper-V)
- Routers/switches Cisco, Fortigate, Mikrotik
- LAN, Vlan, OSPF, FailOver, VPN, SSH
- Ubuntu server, CentOS, Windows Server
- Docker, Bash scripting, Ansible, Databases
- Wireless ISP Technologies

LANGUAGES

French

English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

January 2018 – Current Yaounde, Cameroon

INFORMATION SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

PKFokam Institute of Excellence

Outline

Administered and maintained user accounts for 100+ employees while managing networking infrastructure; ensured 99.99% system uptime and zero data loss, resulting in a seamless IT experience for staff and members.

<u>Achievements</u>

- Take full responsability of IT related business continuity including 100% uptime, full data backup of servers, recovery and system redundancy.
- Develop, maintain and support the company's network and IT security systems
- Oversee the daily server backup routines, ensuring these are completed and remain secure.
- Reduced by 95% critical system downtime with the installation of a monitoring system and realtime failure notification. (Zabbix, Uptime kuma)
- Improved the security of the company's network infrastructure and system architecture by 75% through security policies and vlan implementations, correct configuration of firewalls, routers, switches, Access points and servers.
- Improved staff productivity and security awareness by conducting training sessions. (Phishing mails, Malwares, Passwords regulations)

Nov. 2014 to Dec. 2017

IT BUSINESS ANALYST Junior

Yaounde, Cameroon

PKFokam Institute of Excellence / Research Center

Outline

Serving as a bridge between developpers Team and business stakeholders to ensure that technology solutions meet business needs.

Achievements

- Gathering and analyzing functional requirements and converting to technical requirements.
- Analyzing existing processes and systems to identify gaps and areas for improvement. (Using Docker containers for easy software deployments)
- improved success of IT projects and customers satisfaction by 40% with a good planning and monitoring.

EDUCATION

2013 - 2014 Master Degree 1st Year in Management Information System

Yaounde, Cameroon At Institut Superieur de Technology Appliquée et Gestion (ISTAG)

2012 - 2013 Bachelor Degree in Management Information System

Yaounde, Cameroon At Institut Superieur de Technology Appliquée et Gestion (ISTAG)

CERTIFICATES

2016 - 2017 Cisco Networking Academy Training Certificates (04 modules CCNA)

Yaounde, Cameroon At PKFokam Institute of Excellence

EXTERNAL WORK (IT SUPPORT CONSULTANT)

December 12, 2024 Scope of work: Router installation (ISR1100-4G V02) and SDWan migration

Douala, Cameroon At Base Navale - NILEDUTCH

July 30, 2024 <u>Scope of work</u>: BGP checking/troubleshooting
Yaounde, Cameroon At Brussels Airlines— Nsimalen International Airport

October 09, 2021 Scope of work: Installation of a CISCO 1941/K9 and checking internet

Douala, Cameroon At Ethiopian Airlines – Douala International Airport

PASSIONS

Homelab networking projects (Raspberry pi, Pi-Hole DNS, Active directory, Docker, Zabbix monitoring, Bash scripting, OSPF routing, Vlan...), Photography, Swimming, Speed skating.